Elise A. Weir, PhD

eliseweir@gmail.com | (919) 590-8065 | Memphis, TN 38120 | linkedin.com/in/eliseaweir/ | https://github.com/eliseweir

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software developer with 1 year of experience writing, testing, and delivering back end enterprise code integrated closely with RFID and forklift hardware. Experienced mathematician and educator with a proven history of technical adaptability and strong communication skills.

SKILLS

Languages: Java Spring Boot, Typescript, Python, C++

Technologies: git, npm, Jenkins, gradle, StencilJS, Angular, Ionic, SQL

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer II, FedEx

2/2021 - current

- Supporting maintenance of the current RFID stack using Java Spring Boot, and adding new functionality including REST endpoints.
- Deploying using continuous integration tools, including Jenkins with GitLab hooks.
 Spinning up a Java Spring Boot app from scratch and integrating with existing REST services.
- Writing pages and components for Android and web as part of a special effort to modernize our forklift application using Angular Ionic with custom Stencil components, testing in Jest, Jasmine, and Cypress.
- Building Angular services to call existing REST endpoints.

Visiting Assistant Professor, UCSB Dept. of Mathematics

7/2019 - 6/2020

- Served as the primary instructor for large (80 and 160 student) online calculus classes.
- Taught small upper division classes focused on engaging students in logical thinking.
- Directed small teams of Teaching Assistants in holding recitation sections and grading to provide practice and feedback to students.

EDUCATION

Bootcamp, Web Programming and Code 1.0

9/2021 - 12/2021

Tech901 - tech901.org

- Studied programming basics including logic, functions, and data structures.
- Learned front-end web development in HTML/CSS and JavaScript.

Doctor of Philosophy, Mathematics

2018

University of Tennessee, Knoxville

Emphasis on linear algebra and geometry, and writing code to try out possible theorems.

Bachelor of Science. Honors Mathematics

University of Tennessee, Knoxville

PUBLICATIONS

The Dimension of the Restricted Hitchin Component for Triangle Groups
Doctoral Dissertation available at trace.tennessee.edu/utk_graddiss/5089/

8/2018